http://www.bristol.ac.uk/style-guides/web/policies/legal/privacy/

Privacy and cookies
Overview
In order to operate the University of Bristol ('University') website, we may collect and store personal information you submit to the University via this website. Please read the following privacy policy to understand how the University uses and protects the information that you provide via this website.
This system is provided and hosted by the University. By submitting your personal information, you are consenting to the University holding and using it in accordance with this policy. The policy is subject to change and any changes to it in the future will be notified on this page. By continuing to use this website you are agreeing to such changes. We recommend that you check the privacy policy each time you visit this site.
This website is known by a number of different names. These are bristol.ac.uk, bris.ac.uk, www.bristol.ac.uk, www.bris.ac.uk, bristol.edu and www.bristol.edu. This privacy policy applies to all of these, but not necessarily to others within the bristol.ac.uk, bris.ac.uk and bristol.edu domains. Please note that this website acts as a transparent proxy to some other University of Bristol websites which may be subject to their own privacy policies. Please see our list of proxied sites.
Policy contents
Information that we collect from you and your use of this website
How we use your information
How we handle the data submitted by you
Marketing
Links to external web sites
Changes to our Privacy Policy
How to contact us
1. Information that we collect from you and your use of this website
1.1 Information you give us
When you visit this website you may be asked to provide certain information about yourself, including your name and contact details.
1.2 Automatic Information
We automatically receive and save certain types of information whenever you interact with this website. We use the information to monitor website traffic and to assist with the navigation and user experience of the website.
Information that we will automatically receive includes:
Requested URL (Uniform Resource Locator)
IP (Internet Protocol) address (this may or may not identify a specific computer)
Domain name from which you access the internet
Referring URL
Software (browser/operating system) used to access the page
Date and time pages were visited
1.3 Cookies
Please see the University’s Use of cookies page.
2. How we use your information
We may use and analyse the information we collect so that we can manage and improve the services on the website. Demographic and statistical information about user behaviour may be collected and used to analyse the popularity and effectiveness of the website. Any disclosure of this information will be in aggregate form and will not identify individual users.
The University of Bristol also uses services from Google, comScore and Hotjar on this website to measure and analyse visitor information. For further information on these, please visit comScore, Google Analytics and Hotjar.
The University will not (nor will it allow any third party to) use the statistical analytics tools to track or to collect personally identifiable information of visitors to this website. The University will not associate any data gathered with any personally identifying information from any source as part of our use of the statistical analytics tools.
3. How we handle the data submitted by you
3.1 Data Protection Legislation
The University is the data controller for your personal data that it collects. As your data controller the University has notified its activities to the Office of the Information Commissioner as required under the GDPR and is listed in the Public Register of Data Controllers. Personal information will only be collected and/or processed by the University in accordance with the GDPR.
3.2 Disclosure of your information
Except as set out in this policy or as required by law, your personal data will not be provided to any third party without your prior consent
The information you provide to us will be held on our servers and computers in the UK. It may be accessed by or given to third parties some of whom may be located outside the European Economic Area who act for us for the purposes set out in this policy or for other purposes approved by you. Those parties process information and may provide support services to the University or on the University’s behalf.
Countries outside the European Economic Area do not always have strong data protection laws. However, we will always take appropriate steps to ensure that your information is used securely by third parties in accordance with this policy.
3.3 Monitoring use of University systems
In order to protect the security and working of University network and computer systems, it may be necessary to monitor or log the use of these systems. If there are indications of abuse of systems or that individuals may be using systems in excess of their authority, files, messages and any or all uses of the systems may be intercepted, monitored, recorded, copied, audited, inspected and disclosed to authorised University and law enforcement personnel.
4. Marketing
If you have consented to receive marketing we will use your data to provide you with relevant information about the University, to respond to your enquiries, for quality assurance and market research and to find others who may be interested in receiving information about the University.
We may contact you via email, phone, SMS, post, social and other electronic means, in accordance with your preferences. By agreeing to receive marketing via social and other electronic channels, you agree to us sharing your data with our trusted third parties – under appropriate agreements – who will only use your data for this specific purpose. This may include but is not limited to our digital agencies: RH Advertising, Hybrid Media and Anything is Possible, as well as the Facebook network, Google Display Network, YouTube, Linkedin and Twitter.
Your data will not be sold to any organisation outside the University of Bristol, though it is possible that in limited specific circumstances the University may be required by law to disclose it to external parties.
You have the right to opt out at any point. Please email uob-crm@bristol.ac.uk to update your preferences.
5. Links to external websites
This website may contain links to other websites that are outside the University’s control and are not covered by this privacy policy.
6. Changes to our Privacy Policy
We regularly review our Privacy Policy and updates will appear on this page. This policy was last updated on 11 May 2020.
7. How to contact us
Should the information we hold about you be incorrect, you can change and update your personal information and you can have your information corrected by contacting us.
Where requested, we will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you, by contacting us at the address below. We may require proof of your identity before supplying you with this information to ensure confidentiality.
We allow you to challenge the data we hold about you and where appropriate you may have the data erased, rectified, amended or completed. For complaints or queries about the privacy policy or data protection queries generally please contact:
Data Protection OfficerUniversity of BristolBeacon HouseQueens RoadBristol BS8 1QU, UK
